Register of the Russia. Posol'stvo (U.S.) Records, 1897-1947.
Hoover Institution Archives
- Division of Supplies Office File, 1918-1920.
  - General Chancery
    - Archives
      - Russian Supply Commmittee
        - Commissariat Department (Folder 12)
        - Commission on Purchase Orders (Folder 13)
        - Legal Department (Folder 14)
        - Military Techincal Department (Folder 15)
      - Users (Box 83)
        - 1918 (Folder 1)
        - 1918-1919 (Folder 2)
        - 1919 (Folder 3)
    - Black Tom Island Explosion (Folder 4)
    - Cargoes detained in Denmark--see Inter-Allied Council on War Purchases and Finances, Paris
    - Chikov, V. V. (Folder 5)
    - Claims (Folder 6)
    - Commercial products
      - General (Folder 7)
      - Rails (Folder 8)
        Available on microfilm reel 96
    - Division of Supplies
      - Budget (Folder 9)
      - Diplomatic mail pouch (Folder 10)
      - Personnel
        - General
          - Correspondence (Folder 11)
          - Correspondence (Box 84, Folder 1)
          - Employment records
            - 1918 (Folder 2)
            - 1918-1919 (Folder 3)
            - 1919 (Folder 4)
          - Lists (Folder 5)
          - Memoranda (Folder 6)
        - Director of Supplies (Folder 7)
        - Iasiukovish, M. S., Major-General (Folder 8)
        - Vacations (Folder 9)
      - Subagencies
        - Anglo-Russian Subcommittee and Artillery Storehouses (Folder 10)
        - Artillery Section (Folder 11)
        - Information and Report Section (Folder 12)
        - Machinery Section (Folder 13)
        - Military Section (Folder 14)
          Available on microfilm reel 97
        - Military Section and Naval Section (Folder 15)
        - Mission of Ways of Communication (Folder 16)
        - Naval Section (Folder 17)
        - Transportation and Warehouse Section (Folder 18)
    - Golokhvastov, Vladimir (Folder 19)
    - Guaranty Trust Company--see Morton Truck and Tractor Company
    - Inter-Allied Council on War Purchases and Finance, Paris (Folder 20)
    - Jewish charitable organizations--see American Red Cross
    - Kokh, Nikolai, Colonel (Folder 21)
    - Kondrat'ev, Dmitrii (Folder 22)
    - Lehigh Valley Railraod Company--see Black Tom Island Explosion
    - Martens, L. (Folder 23)
    - Maryland Casualty Company (Folder 24)
    - Morton Truck and Tractor Company (Folder 25)
    - Nekrasov, Colonel (Folder 26)
    - New York Telephone Company (Folder 27)
    - Ozol's, Karl (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Paikin, A. M. (Folder 2)
    - Pelekhovish, Kirill (Folder 3)
    - Pioneer Fireproof Storage Warehouses, New York (Folder 4)
    - Pykhteev, Anatolii (Folder 5)
    - Real Estate Management (Folder 6)
    - Refugees, Russian in the United States. Questionnaires
      - 1918
        - September
          - 16-33 (Folder 7)
          - 24-31 (Folder 8)
            Available on microfilm reel 98
        - October
          - 5-10 (Folder 9)
          - 11-14 (Folder 10)
          - 18-31 (Folder 11)
        - November (Box 86, Folder 1)
      - 1919 (Folder 2)
    - Russian State Control (Folder 3)
    - Russian Supply Committee (Folder 4)
      Available on microfilm reel 99
    - Russo-Baltic Car Works (Folder 5)
    - Shevchenko, K. (Folder 6)
    - Slastenin, Lieutenant (Folder 7)
    - Standard Shipbuilding Corporation (Folder 8)
    - Tarasov, A. C. (Folder 9)
    - Tennessee Copper Company--see Black Tom Island Explosion
    - Typewriters (Folder 10)
    - Umanskii, L. A. (Folder 11)
    - United States Army -- drafting of aliens (Folder 12)
    - United States War Trade Board (Folder 13)
    - Western Union Telegraph Company (Folder 14)
  - General Section
    - General
      - Correspondence
        - General (Folder 15)
        - Russian Embassy, Washington
          - First Secretary
            - 1918-1919 (Folder 16)
              Available on microfilm reel 100
            - 1919-1920 (Folder 17)
            - 1920 (Folder 18)
          - Military Agent (Box 87, Folder 1)
          - Military Agent and Naval Agent (Folder 2)
          - Naval Agent (Folder 3)
          - Russian State Control
            - 1919-1920 (Folder 4)
            - 1920
              - April-October (Folder 5)
              - September-October (Folder 6)
        - Secret (Folder 7)
        - Wallace, D. E., British Military Attache in the United States (Folder 8)
      - Financial records
        - 1918-1919 (Folder 9)
        - 1920
          - January-March (Folder 10)
          - February-October (Folder 11)
      - Orders
        - 1919 (Folder 12-13)
          Available on microfilm reel 101
        - 1920 (Folder 14-16)
    - Ageev, Aleksandr (Folder 17)
    - Ageev, Aleksandr (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - American Russian Chamber of Commerce (Folder 2)
    - Archives -- subagency
      - General
        - Receipts (Folder 3)
        - Reports
          - 1919 (Folder 4)
          - 1919-1920 (Folder 5)
        - Statements (Folder 6)
      - Division of Supplies
        - n.d. (Folder 7)
        - 1920
          - March (Folder 8)
          - June (Folder 9)
      - Division of Supplies and Russian Supply Committee
        - Artillery subagencies (Folder 10)
        - Financial subagencies (Folder 11)
        - Transportation subagencies
          - 1919-1920 (Folder 12)
            Available on microfilm reel 102
      - Khrabrov, Nikolai (Folder 13)
      - Russian Supply Committee. (see also Division of Supplies and Russian Supply Committee) (Folder 14)
        - General (Folder 15)
        - Agricultural Department (Folder 16)
        - Artillery Commission (Folder 17)
        - Commissariat Department (Folder 18)
        - Machinery Department (Folder 19)
        - Transportation Department (Folder 20)
          Available on microfilm reel 103
      - Users (Box 89)
        - 1919-1920 (Folder 1)
        - 1920 (Folder 2)
      - Bobrovichii, Vasilii (Folder 3)
      - Building management, 1920
        - April-June (Folder 4)
        - June-July (Folder 5)
    - Claims
      - General
        - 1919-1920 (Folder 6)
        - 1920 (Folder 7-8)
      - Black Tom Island Explosion (Folder 9)
        Available on microfilm reel 104
      - Great Britain. Ministry of Shipping (Folder 10)
      - New York Central Railroad Company (Folder 11)
      - Paterson, New Jersey (Folder 12)
      - Seager Trading Company (Folder 13)
      - Standard Shipbuilding Corporation (Folder 14)
      - Straus, E. A. & Company (Folder 15)
    - Commercial products. (see also Ageev, Aleksandr; Freighters) (Box 90)
      - General
        - 1919-1920 (Folder 1)
        - 1920 (Folder 2)
      - Books and microscopes (Folder 3)
      - Coal (Folder 4)
      - Microscopes--see Books and microscopes
      - Rails (Folder 5)
        Available on microfilm reel 105
      - Warehouses
        - Eddystone Storage Co.--see General Section/ Commercial products/1920
        - Jarvis Stores, Inc., New York
          - 1919-1920 (Folder 6)
          - 1920 (Folder 7)
        - Merchants Warehouse Company. (see also General Section/Commercial products/1920) (Folder 8)
        - Pioneer Fireproof Storage Warehouse Company, New York (Folder 9)
        - Quincy Market Cold Storage, Boston (Folder 10)
        - Terry, W. M. Company, Bridgeport, Connecticut
        - Thos. E. Garvey Forwarding Storage Company, New York (Folder 11)
    - Division of Supplies
      - Budget
        - 1919-1920 (Folder 12-13)
        - 1920 (Folder 14)
      - Diplomatic mail pouch (Box 91, Folder 1)
      - Composition and structure
        - General
          - 1919-1920 (Folder 2)
          - 1920 (Folder 3)
        - Dismissals
          - 1919-1920 (Folder 4-5)
            Available on microfilm reel 106
          - 1920
            - April-October (Folder 6)
            - May-September (Folder 7)
        - Financial claims of former employees
          - 1919-1920 (Folder 8)
          - 1920 (Folder 9)
        - Iasiukovich, M. S., Major-General (Folder 10)
      - Subagencies
        - Anglo-Russian Subcommittee and Artillery Storehouses
          - 1919 (Folder 11)
          - 1919-1920 (Folder 12)
        - Commission on Claims -- board sessions (Folder 13)
        - Mission of Ways of Communication (Folder 14-15)
        - Russian Remington Rifle Contract Trustee
          - Agreement of 29 July 1919 between Remington Arms Company and Division of Supplies (Folder 16)
          - Commercial products (Box 92)
            - General
              - 1919 (Folder 1)
                Available on microfilm reel 107
              - 1920 (Folder 2)
            - Rifles (Folder 3)
          - Personnel (Folder 4)
          - United States Government -- claims (Folder 5-6)
        - Transportation and Warehouse Section
          - General (Folder 7-8)
            Folder 7 available on microfilm reel 107 and folder 8 available on microfilm reel 108
          - Gerasimov, I. V.
            - 1919 (Folder 9)
              Available on microfilm reel 108
            - 1919-1920 (Folder 10)
            - 1920 (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Eddystone Ammunition Corporation (Folder 2)
    - Efimov, Viacheslav (Folder 3)
    - Freighters. (see also Ageev, Aleksandr)
      - General
        - 1919-1920 (Folder 4)
        - 1920
          - January-February (Folder 5)
          - February-March (Folder 6)
            Available on microfilm reel 109
          - March-September (Folder 7)
      - Balsam, Pawnee, Sangamon
        - 1919-1920 (Folder 8)
        - 1920 (Folder 9)
      - Cardareta (Box 94, Folder 1)
      - Dora, Oconee, Pawnee (Folder 2)
      - Dora, Vologda (Folder 3)
      - Eastern Victor (Folder 4)
      - Hog Island (Folder 5)
      - Homestead
        - 1919-1920 (Folder 6)
          Available on microfilm reel 110
        - 1920 (Folder 7)
      - Kursk (Folder 8)
      - Mulpua (Folder 9)
      - Mulpua and Nizhnii Novgorod (Folder 10)
      - Nizhnii Novgorod--see Mulpua and Nizhnii Novgorod
      - Oconee--see Dora, Oconee, Pawnee
      - Omsk
        - 1919-1920 (Folder 11)
        - 1920
          - March (Folder 12)
          - June (Folder 13)
          - June-July (Folder 14)
          - July-August (Box 95, Folder 1)
            Available on microfilm reel 111
          - August-October (Folder 2)
      - Pawnee--see Balsam, Pawnee, Sangamon; and Dora, Oconee, Pawnee
      - Rodgai
        - 1919 (Folder 3)
        - 1920 (Folder 4)
      - Sangamon. (see also Balsam, Pawnee, Sangamon)
        - 1919-1920 (Folder 5)
        - 1920 (Folder 6)
          Available on microfilm reel 112
      - Shinsey Maru (Folder 7)
      - Supervisory staff (Folder 8)
      - Vologda (Box 96)
        - A. B. Abo Jernmanufaktur och Waggonfabrik O.-Y., Finland (Folder 1)
        - Gerhard & Hey, Inc.--see A. B. Abo Jernmanufaktur och Waggonfabrik O.-Y., Finland
        - Richards, C. B. & Company (Folder 2)
        - Westmount (Folder 3)
    - Grace American International Corporation (Folder 4)
    - Holmes Electric Protective Company (Folder 5)
    - Iaremenko, Ensign (Folder 6)
    - Insurance companies--see Real Estate management
    - Iudenich, General, Army of--see Refugees, Russian/Army of General Iudenich
    - Kerenskii ruble notes (Folder 7)
    - Kokh, Nikolai, Colonel (Folder 8)
    - Kondrat'ev, Dmitrii (Folder 9)
    - Martens, L. (Folder 10)
    - Maryland Casualty Company (Folder 11)
    - New York Telephone Company (Folder 12)
    - Northern Pacific Railway Company, Seattle (Folder 13)
    - Office supply
      - 1919-1920 (Folder 14)
        - General (Folder 15-16)
        - Typewriters (Folder 17)
          Available on microfilm reel 113
      - 1920
        - General (Folder 18)
        - Typewriters (Folder 19)
    - Polovtsev, Nikolai (Folder 20)
    - Poluboiarinov, A. D. (Folder 22)
    - Prokof'ev, Sergei. Letters--see Claims/General/1919- 1920 (Folder 23)
    - Refugees, Russian
      - General (Folder 24)
      - Army of General Iudenich (Folder 25)
    - Russia
      - Revolution, 1917-1921 -- Counterrevolutionary movements
        - General--see General Section/Russian anti- Bolshevik governments
        - General--see General Section/Russian Foreign Supply Board; and General Section/United States American Relief Administration
        - Far East--see Siberia and Far East
        - Siberia and Far East--see General Section/ Ageev, Aleksandr and Freighters/Omsk/ 1919-1920 and 1920/June
        - South--see General Section/Commercial products/Coal and Freighters/Balsam, Pawnee, Sangamon and also Omsk/1919-1920 and 1920/June
      - Social and economic conditions--see General Section/American Russian Chamber of Commerce
    - Russian anti-Bolshevik governments (Box 97)
      - Foreign supply (Folder 1)
      - Rules of import (Folder 2)
    - Russian Embassy, Washington
      - Commission for Reviewing Petitions for Assistance, 1920
        - May-August (Folder 3)
        - August-October (Folder 4)
      - Committee for Collecting Clothes and Money for Soldiers of Russian Armies (Folder 5)
      - Consulate General, New York
        - American market. Reports (Folder 6)
        - Russian citizens living abroad -- rules and regulations (Folder 7)
      - Financial agent
        - 1919-1920 (Folder 8)
          Available on microfilm reel 114
        - 1920
          - February (Folder 9)
          - October (Folder 10)
      - Russian Supply Committee (Folder 11)
    - Russian Foreign Supply Board, Paris (Folder 12)
    - Union of Siberian Creamery Associations. (see also Freighters/Mulpua) (Box 98)
      - Russian Government. Contracts. (see also United States Government)
        - 1919 (Folder 1)
        - 1920 (Folder 2)
      - United States Government. Contracts and correspondence
        - General (Folder 3)
        - Commercial products (Folder 4)
        - Payment
          - 1919-1920 (Folder 5)
          - 1920 (Folder 6)
    - United States
      - American Relief Administration (Folder 7)
      - Army. Ordnance Department (Folder 8)
        Available on microfilm reel 115
      - Navy Yard--see General Section/Freighters/Dora, Oconee, Pawnee
      - Shipping Board. (see also General Section/ Freighters/General) (Folder 9)
    - Znamenskii, Ivan, Deputy Minister of Supplies, Omsk. (see also Union of Siberian Creamery Associations)
      - 1919-1920 (Folder 10)
      - 1920 (Folder 11)
  - Information and Report Section (Box 99)
    - Brazol', Boris (Folder 1)
    - Division of Supplies
      - Commissariat Section (Folder 2)
      - Commission on Russian Freighters Returned by the United States Shipping Board (Folder 3)
      - Financial Section (Folder 4)
      - General Chancery (Folder 5)
    - Gaston, Williams & Wigmore Co. (see also Wisconsin Bridge) (Folder 6)
    - Morton Truck and Tractor Co. (Folder 7)
    - Personnel
      - Correspondence (Folder 8)
      - Overtime slips (Folder 9)
    - Petrograd Zemstvos and Cities Regional Committee
      - "Kratkii obzor deiatel'nosti Komissii v Amerike" (Folder 10)
      - Paterson, New Jersey (Folder 11)
    - Russian Supply Committee, Report
      - Draft
        - General (Folder 12)
        - Financial Department (Folder 13)
        - Naval Department (Folder 14)
      - "Otchet o deiatel'nosti Russkogo zagotovitel'nogo komiteta v Amerike i ego Likvidatsionnoi komissii" (Box 100)
        - Part 1 (Folder 1-2)
          Available on microfilm reel 116
        - Part 2
          - Volume 1 (Folder 3-4)
            Available on microfilm reel 117
          - Volume 2 (Box 101, Folder 1-2)
            Available on microfilm reels 117 and 118
          - Volume 3 (Folder 3-4)
            Available on microfilm reel 118
    - Wisconsin Bridge, Freighter (Folder 5)
  - Inspection Department (Box 102, Folder 1)
    Available on microfilm reel 119
  - Mission of Ways of Communication
    - General
      - Contracts (Folder 2)
      - Orders (Folder 3)
      - Report. "Otchet o deiatel'nosti Missii Ministerstva Putei Soobshcheniia v Amerike"
        - 1918-1919 (Folder 4-5)
        - 1919-1920
          - Mimeographed copies (Folder 6-7)
          - Appendix (Folder 8)
    - Books--see Microscopes and books (Box 103)
    - Claims. (see also Freighters/Carolyn; and Northern Pacific Railway Company, Seattle)
      - 1919-1920 (Folder 1)
      - 1920 (Folder 2)
    - Freighters
      - General (Folder 3)
        Available on microfilm reel 120
      - Carolyn (Folder 4)
    - Independent Stores, New York (Folder 5-6)
    - Microscopes and books (Folder 7)
    - Northern Pacific Railway Company, Seattle (Folder 8)
    - Rails (Box 104, Folder 1)
      Available on microfilm reel 121
    - Seifert, L. F.'s Sons, Inc., Philadelphia (Folder 2)
  - Naval Section (Folder 3)
  - Russian Remington Rifle Contract Trustee -- "Plan sostavleniia kratkogo otcheta o deiatel'nosti Komissii po priemke imushchestva na zavode Remingtona" (Folder 4)
  - Transportation and Warehouse Section
    - Board sessions. Minutes (Folder 5)
    - Commercial products (Folder 6)
    - Left wing movement in the United States--see Westmount, Freighter -- loading arms against the Bolsheviks. Clippings, reports of a secret agent
    - Russian intelligence service--see Westmount, Freighter
    - Westmount, Freighter -- loading arms against the Bolsheviks. Clippings, reports of a secret agent (Folder 7)
- Financial Agent Office File, 1917-1935.
  Available on microfilm reels 121-287
  Administrative orders, affidavits, clippings, correspondence, financial records, memoranda, notes, printed matter, reports, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - General (Box 105)
    - Clippings
      - 1920-1921 (Folder 1)
      - 1921-1922 (Folder 2)
      - 1922 (Folder 3)
        Available on microfilm reel 122
    - Correspondence
      - General
        - General
          - 1921-1922 (Folder 4)
          - 1922 (Folder 5)
          - 1922-1923 (Folder 6)
          - 1923
            - March-August (Folder 7)
            - September-December (Folder 8)
          - 1924
            - January-June (Folder 9)
              Available on microfilm reel 123
            - July-December (Box 106, Folder 1)
          - 1924-1926 (Folder 2)
          - 1926-1927 (Folder 3)
          - 1927-1928 (Folder 4-5)
            Available on microfilm reels 123 and 124
          - 1928-1929 (Folder 6)
            Available on microfilm reel 124
          - 1929-1930 (Box 107, Folder 1-2)
          - 1930-1931 (Folder 3)
          - 1931-1932 (Folder 4)
          - 1932-1933 (Folder 5)
          - 1933-1934 (Folder 6)
            Available on microfilm reel 125
        - Inquiries
          - 1921-1922 (Folder 7)
          - 1922-1924 (Folder 8)
          - 1924 (Box 108, Folder 1)
          - 1924-1925 (Folder 2)
          - 1925-1926 (Folder 3)
            Available on microfilm reel 126
          - 1926 (Folder 4)
          - 1926-1927 (Folder 5)
          - 1927 (Folder 6)
          - 1928
            - January-July (Folder 7)
            - August-December (Folder 8)
          - 1928-1929 (Box 109, Folder 1)
            Available on microfilm reel 127
          - 1929 (Folder 2)
          - 1929-1930 (Folder 3)
          - 1930-1931 (Folder 4)
          - 1931 (Folder 5)
          - 1931-1932 (Folder 6)
            Available on microfilm reel 128
          - 1932 (Folder 7)
          - 1932-1935 (Folder 8)
        - Reference letters (Box 110)
          - 1920 (Folder 1)
          - 1921-1922 (Folder 2)
          - 1922-1924 (Folder 3)
          - 1924-1931 (Folder 4)
            Available on microfilm reel 129
        - Solicitation letters
          - 1920-1921 (Folder 5)
          - 1921-1922 (Folder 6)
      - Coudert Brothers
        - 1922-1924 (Folder 7)
        - 1924-1928 (Folder 8)
        - 1927-1935 (Box 111, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 130
      - Girs, Mikhail
        - 1922-1926 (Folder 2)
        - 1927-1928 (Folder 3)
      - Russian Embassy, Washington (Folder 4)
      - United States Government
        - State Department
          - 1922 (Folder 5)
          - 1923-1927 (Folder 6)
          - 1927-1932 (Folder 7)
            Available on microfilm reel 131
          - 1933-1935 (Folder 8)
        - Treasury Department
          - 1920-1921 (Folder 9)
          - 1922-1923 (Folder 10)
          - 1924 (Box 112, Folder 1)
          - 1924-1926 (Folder 2)
          - 1926-1930 (Folder 3)
    - Day file
      - 1920
        - November
          - 1-12 (Folder 4)
            Available on microfilm reel 132
          - 13-20 (Folder 5)
          - 20-30 (Folder 6)
        - December
          - 1-11 (Folder 7)
          - 11-23 (Folder 8)
          - 23-31 (Folder 9)
            Available on microfilm reel 133
      - 1921 (Box 113)
        - January
          - 3-14 (Folder 1)
          - 14-21 (Folder 2)
        - January-February (Folder 3)
        - February (Folder 4)
        - February-March (Folder 5)
        - March (Folder 6)
        - March-April (Folder 7)
          Available on microfilm reel 134
        - April (Folder 8)
        - April-May (Folder 9)
        - May
          - 4-23 (Folder 10)
          - 23-31 (Box 114, Folder 1)
        - June (Folder 2)
        - June-July (Folder 3)
          Available on microfilm reel 135
        - July (Folder 4)
        - July-August (Folder 5)
        - August-September (Folder 6)
        - September-October (Folder 7)
        - October (Folder 8)
          Available on microfilm reel 136
        - October-November (Folder 9)
        - November-December (Box 115, Folder 1)
        - December (Folder 2)
      - 1922
        - January (Folder 3)
          Available on microfilm reel 137
        - January-Febraury (Folder 4)
        - February-March (Folder 5)
        - March-April (Folder 6)
        - April (Folder 7)
        - May (Folder 8)
          Available on microfilm reel 138
        - May-June (Folder 9)
        - July (Box 116, Folder 1)
        - July-August (Folder 2)
        - August (Folder 3)
        - August-September (Folder 4)
          Available on microfilm reel 139
        - September
          - 8-14 (Folder 5)
          - 14-30 (Folder 6)
        - September-October (Folder 7)
        - October-November (Folder 8)
        - November-December (Folder 9)
          Available on microfilm reel 140
      - 1922-1923 (Box 117, Folder 1)
      - 1923
        - January-February (Folder 2)
        - February-March (Folder 3)
        - March-April (Folder 4)
          Available on microfilm reel 141
        - April (Folder 5)
        - May-June (Folder 6)
        - June (Folder 7)
        - July (Box 118, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 142
        - July-August (Folder 2)
        - August-September (Folder 3)
        - September (Folder 4)
        - September-October (Folder 5)
          Available on microfilm reel 143
        - October-November (Folder 6)
        - November-December (Folder 7)
        - December (Folder 8)
      - 1924 (Box 119)
        - January-February (Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 144
        - February (Folder 2)
        - March-April (Folder 3)
        - April (Folder 4)
        - April-May (Folder 5)
          Available on microfilm reel 145
        - May (Folder 6)
        - June-July (Folder 7)
        - July-August (Folder 8)
        - August-September (Folder 9)
        - September (Folder 10)
          Available on microfilm reel 146
        - October (Box 120, Folder 1)
        - November (Folder 2)
        - December (Folder 3)
      - 1925
        - January (Folder 4)
        - January-February (Folder 5)
          Available on microfilm reel 147
        - February-March (Folder 6)
        - March-April (Folder 7)
        - April (Folder 8)
        - April-May (Folder 9)
        - June-July (Box 121, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 148
        - July (Folder 2)
        - August-September (Folder 3)
        - September (Folder 4)
        - October (Folder 5)